<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The people of England's grievances offered to be enquired into, and redress'd by their representatives in Parliament</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 22KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A54289</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12602432</idno>
  <idno type="VID">64195</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240950281</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1444</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R18299</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12602432</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A54289)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 64195)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 771:20)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The people of England's grievances offered to be enquired into, and redress'd by their representatives in Parliament</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1660-1714.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="grievances">
            <pb facs="tcp:64195:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:64195:1"/>
            <head>The <hi>People</hi> of <hi>England</hi>'s GRIEVANCES offered to be <hi>Enquired</hi> into, and <hi>Redress'd</hi> by their <hi>Representatives</hi> in <hi>Parliament.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE present Government, under which we expected so much Happiness, doth so sensibly decay in the good Opinion and Affections of all sorts of People, that nothing but the timely Help of the approaching Parliament can pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent those dangers which otherwise the general Want of Affection in too many Men of all ranks seem to portend unto it.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Monday,</hi> the first day of the Term, <hi>Westminster-hall</hi> was filled with loud Complaints and Threatenings against the great Men, for Imprisoning Peers and Commoners contrary to Law. One brave Peer, whose great Years cannot abate the Fervour of his juvenile Courage, by which he rendred himself so famous, and enobled his Posterity, spake aloud against Foreigners, and foreign Counsels; his Share in the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment could not prevail with him to hide its Defects and wrong measures, to the astonishment of the Hearers: And the very same day at the <hi>Royal Exchange,</hi> as if the Citizens had been acted with the same Spirit of Discontent, they talked loudly of their Losses by Sea, and the Male-administration of the Navy, cursing the Dutch, and reciting their Losses since the Revolution, to the value of several Millions. The two or three next days following, and ever since, we have heard our Sea-men bitterly cursing in the Streets for want of their Pay; and our Land-Forces, newly arrived from <hi>Flanders,</hi> cursing as bitterly for their ill Usage there: Nay, the very Officers that are come from thence, and some of them Members of Parliament, curse the <hi>Dutch</hi> as bitterly in private as their Soldiers do in the Streets: They tell us, without re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>serve, of the unequal treatment abroad of them and the <hi>Dutch;</hi> these are paid, while they and their Men scarce have Subsistance; and yet they must be called out to fight the Battels, in truth, of the <hi>Dutch,</hi> who stand looking on, and must not come to their Relief.</p>
            <p>The Common People are also querelous in almost all places, they complain aloud of the Weight and Number of our Taxes, while Books are written, complaining of the Male-administration from the first over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sight in not relieving <hi>Ireland;</hi> as also of the loss of so many brave <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glish-men</hi>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:64195:2"/> for want of being relieved and succoured at the Battel of <hi>Steyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kirk;</hi> as likewise the Miscariage of the Descent. From <hi>these Books,</hi> and the <hi>free Discourses</hi> of such <hi>true Patriots</hi> as <hi>wrote</hi> them, the Nation is perfectly informed how empty we are left of Stores and Ammunition, by the consumption of those King <hi>James</hi> left, to the value of Thirteen hundred thousand Pounds, and by sending abroad great Trains of Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tillery. By them we come to know that foreign Commodities are ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sen 30 <hi>per Cent.</hi> and that ours are fallen 20 <hi>per Cent.</hi> That great num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of Land-men, Natives of this Kingdom, were press'd against Law, and the Liberty of the Subject, for Sea service, and sold into <hi>Flanders</hi> against their Consent. That our best Coin is exported into <hi>Holland</hi> and <hi>Flanders,</hi> and a great part of it there clipt and demolished; and that our Forces are there abused with the change of our Guineas which have escaped melting down. That above two hundred thousand <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glish men</hi> have been lost by the War since the Revolution; and that the Government hath spent above two and twenty Millions, and (as pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended) is six in debt, or thereabouts. That Parliament Men have been closetted of late, and that in <hi>Flanders,</hi> as well as <hi>England.</hi> That Conspiracies and Associations have been forged against Peers and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moners; and the Forgers of them, though so palpably detected, not prosecuted till lately, that the Parliament was ready to meet, who had voted that the Attorney General should proceed against <hi>Fuller.</hi> That a free-born <hi>English-man</hi> hath been tortured in <hi>Scotland</hi> by order from <hi>England,</hi> against all Law and Example; and also against Law con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fined, and so continues without new Evidence, after he had endured Torture. That Men of all degrees are injured and opprest more than ever, with enormous and excessive Fines and Bail, against the Articles of Government. That places of Trust, both Civil and Military, are sold; and that the Kingdom is full of foreign Forces, to the terrour of our own People. That the publick Moneys, given and designed solely for the defence and preservation of the Nation, have been misapplied, of which, though many Instances might be given, I shall for brevity sake onely instance in one: It appears by the publick Accompts delive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red in to Parliament, that two thousand seven hundred and fifty pounds were paid to the Earl of <hi>Sunderland,</hi> one excepted out of the <hi>Act of Grace;</hi> and to whom the Nation is onely indebted, for the dreadfull Calamities (the Effects of his Management and Advices) which have befaln it.</p>
            <p>These things, and many more which might be recited, have bred in many an Indifferency for the Government, who were before well af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fected to it; and others dislike it to that degree, as to wish for a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-wealth, or any thing that may give them Ease. It is the great Zeal I have to prevent the ruine of my Countrey, as much as lies in my
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:64195:2"/> single Capacity, that makes me write this short Summary of our <hi>Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances,</hi> and set it in the view of our Representatives, who are onely capable to make an effectual Enquiry into the true Causes of them, and remove them. Some of them indeed are apparently the Causes of o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers; but there is undoubtedly some general Cause or Causes of them all: And if the Voice of the People, by which I understand People of all ranks, speaks truth, <hi>Dutch Counsels</hi> and <hi>Dutch Measures</hi> of acting are the true source of all these Mischiefs; or else, how come they to curse the <hi>Dutch,</hi> in the Court and in the Camp, in the City and in the Country, by Sea and Land, both here and in <hi>Flanders;</hi> and the <hi>English</hi> Hatred of the <hi>French</hi> is turning apace, in all sorts of Men, into an Hatred of the <hi>Dutch:</hi> Our very Soldiers by Sea and Land, as well as their Commanders, wish for a War against the <hi>Dutch;</hi> and Parliament Men enough complain, that they shall never get some Bills pass for the benefit of this Kingdom, because they are contrary to the Interest of the <hi>Dutch.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I must avow, I cannot tell what need an <hi>English</hi> King hath of <hi>Dutch</hi> Counsellours: It is enough that he govern by them in the <hi>Ʋnited Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vinces,</hi> and by <hi>Englishmen</hi> in <hi>England;</hi> as if he were crowned King of <hi>France,</hi> (for which some hope his good Fortune reserves him,) he must not expect to govern that Kingdom by <hi>English</hi> Counsels; for the <hi>French</hi> would never endure <hi>English</hi> Ministers, or <hi>English</hi> Counsels, or <hi>English</hi> Forces; nor do I know why the <hi>English</hi> should endure the <hi>Dutch.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It is the Expectation of all true <hi>Englishmen,</hi> that the Parliament will at last remove this Cause of our Calamities, before they give any more Money; but if they do not, they will give to their own and our De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>struction, and repent when it is too late.</p>
            <p>His Majesty being King of <hi>England,</hi> as such is one of the greatest crowned Heads of <hi>Europe,</hi> and it would be an unspeakable Satisfaction to his People, if he would be pleased to quit his Stadtholdership in <hi>Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> for <hi>England</hi> and the <hi>Ʋnited Provinces</hi> are Rivals for the Trade of the World, and as such have mighty crossing and interfering Interests, and will be always jealous of one another.</p>
            <p>Another Cause of our Calamities, proceeding in part from the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, is, as many suspect, the Corruption of some Members of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, who do not give but sell their Votes. This is a great reproach to our Nation, under a <hi>Reforming Government,</hi> and hath been the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint of some in the House, as well as without doors; and it is the desire and expectation of all true <hi>Englishmen,</hi> before any more of our Money be given, that the Commissioners appointed and enabl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amine the publick Accompts of the Kingdom, do take and require an Accompt upon Oath from the respective Officers, of all the Pensions, Salaries, and Summs of Money, paid or payable out of the Revenue or
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:64195:3"/> otherwise, to <hi>Members of Parliament,</hi> and that Accompt so taken be delivered into <hi>Parliament.</hi> No sound Member can oppose such an En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiry, and if upon making of it any <hi>Pensioners</hi> (as they are called) can be found, it will be an Honour to the House, and a Satisfaction to the Nation, to have the House purged of them; or if none should be found, it will yet be a greater Honour to the House, and a full Satisfaction to the People, to know there are no such Members among them in this <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed Reign.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>These are some among many other Enquiries, which we hope our Representatives will make, and redress what <hi>Grievances</hi> they find, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they give any more of our Money; the Love of their Groaning Countrey, and their Honour as <hi>Englishmen,</hi> and as <hi>Trustees</hi> of the <hi>English People,</hi> we cannot but think will oblige them to it.</p>
            <p>I have said nothing of the <hi>General Excise,</hi> because it cannot enter into my Heart to think that the Conservators of our Liberties will lay Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>positions upon the Necessaries of Life; for though a Nation may en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dure it whereof nine parts in ten live on <hi>Trade,</hi> yet it can never be endu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red long in a Country where the same proportion live upon <hi>Land,</hi> and not on <hi>Trade,</hi> as the Dutch do. I speak of a <hi>General Excise,</hi> which takes in <hi>Bread, Flesh, Salt, Soap, Tallow, Leather,</hi> or other Commodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, absolutely necessary for the Subsistance of the poor as well as the rich of the Nation, which I aver will ruine our Countrey, and if it be not so <hi>General</hi> will not answer the Ends for which it is imposed: The <hi>fourth</hi> or <hi>fifth Penny</hi> will go away in such a <hi>General Excise,</hi> which is as much as most people lay up, or <hi>can</hi> lay up for their Children; but if that share must go to the <hi>Government</hi> out of our necessary Expences, <hi>God be mercifull unto us, and to the miserable Posterity which we shall leave behind us.</hi> I shall say nothing of the Legions of Excise-men which must then live upon our Vitals. The <hi>French</hi> will be then by much the <hi>happier People,</hi> when this <hi>Gabell</hi> shall be established: Some say it shall be given but for the time the War shall last; but I say, if it once be given, the Government will never want a pretence of Necessity to keep it up in time of <hi>Peace</hi> as well as <hi>War;</hi> and when it is once up, <hi>adieu</hi> to <hi>free Parliaments,</hi> and then who shall pull it down?</p>
            <p>It is already given in the Intention of some; for one <hi>Parker, Agent</hi> for the <hi>Dutch Bankers,</hi> is come out of <hi>Holland</hi> with a <hi>Plan</hi> or <hi>Method,</hi> there contrived, of raising it here in <hi>England;</hi> and with a proposition, that the <hi>Dutch</hi> Bankers, who cannot but be supposed to doe it by the Direction of the States General, will advance some Millions on that Fond, as soon as granted; by which they will in a short time devour the <hi>whole Treasure of the Nation:</hi> For in <hi>Holland</hi> Money is put out but at 3 <hi>per Cent.</hi> and for Money put into the Exchequer here 8 <hi>per Cent.</hi> is allowed: So that the <hi>Dutch</hi> will thereby be clear Gainers 5 <hi>per Cent.</hi>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:64195:3"/> and 6 <hi>per Cent.</hi> for remitting our Money into <hi>Holland.</hi> Wherefore such an Excise will not onely impoverish our Countrey, but enslave us to the <hi>Dutch,</hi> by enriching them, and helping to maintain greater Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of foreign Forces, who have no Principle, but to <hi>fight for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ay.</hi> It is found by Experience, that they will fight as they are commanded, as well against as for our Religion and Liberties. Duke <hi>Schomberg</hi>'s Declaration in <hi>Dauphiny</hi> (as in the original <hi>French)</hi> hath helped to open our Eyes; and it is most certain, that Foreigners in the Confederacy fight more for <hi>our Money</hi> than the <hi>Protestant Religion,</hi> and make <hi>new Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gains</hi> against every Campaign.</p>
            <p>I shall not presume to direct our Representatives what is fit to be le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied for the carrying on of the War; but I must beg leave to acquaint them, that as it is not to be doubted but that they will be minded of their Promise, to make up the <hi>Poll▪ Bill</hi> 1300000 <hi>l.</hi> which is said not to amount to above 800000 <hi>l.</hi> so it is to be hoped, before they give the remaining Balance, 500000 <hi>l.</hi> they will please to enquire, whether for carrying on the <hi>Descent</hi> which was to be made into <hi>France,</hi> the full num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of 38000 Men were raised and paid, that being the <hi>Quota</hi> assigned for that particular Service in the Account of 65000 Men to be raised and maintained for one whole year, for the defraying of the Charges where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the Parliament so frankly gave the full Summ demanded.</p>
            <p>And before I conclude I shall take Liberty to acquaint our Representa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives in Parliament, that the Nation expects that they shall either ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriate what they give this Session to the use of the War, and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point Commissioners to receive it, and issue out the payments of it to that intent and purpose, and no other; or in case they think not fit to do this, then it will be expected, that they will make all Officers what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soever, appointed to receive and issue out any of the said Money, liable to the penalties of perpetual Disability for any Office, Civil or Mili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tary, and an Incapacity to sit in either House of Parliament, if they or any of them shall issue out or misapply any of the said Money to any other use or purpose; as also to an Action from any person or persons who shall advance Mony, or furnish any Stores or Habiliments for War by Sea or Land upon the Fond of the said Money, which shall be appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priated to the aforesaid Use.</p>
            <p>It is also to be desired, that they will require all <hi>English</hi> Officers, Civil and Military, to bring a true Account of the just Arrears due to them, and all Persons employed under them on the publick Service, and vote all such Arrears to be paid out of some Branch of the publick Revenue, as may be most easie to the Kingdom.</p>
            <p>But it is to be hoped when you enquire into the Receipt of the Mony brought into the Exchequer this last year, and the Disbursements, there will there remain money, more than sufficient, to pay all Arrears due
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:64195:4"/> to the Land and Sea Forces; for the Customs have this last year clearly brought in Eight hundred thousand pounds, the hereditary Excise Six hundred thousand, the double Excise Four hundred thousand, the small Branches of the Revenue Forty thousand, the Land Tax Sixteen hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred thousand, and admit that the quadruple Poll brought in but Eight hundred thousand pound, the total of this Year's receipts amounts to Four Millions, two hundred and forty thousand pounds; which, with Eighteen Millions given before, since the <hi>Revolution,</hi> amounts to above Two and twenty Millions, received by the Government: And if that hath not been sufficient to defray the Charge of the War, and all the necessary Expences of the Government, with a Summ remaining in Banck sufficient to discharge all Arrears, then the Nation must sink under the Burthen, unless our Representatives can find out a way to lessen the <hi>Charge</hi> of the Government, and encrease the <hi>Riches</hi> of the Kingdom.</p>
            <p>And whether or no that will not in a great measure be done by open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing our Trade with <hi>France,</hi> (even during the continuance of the War) will be worth their Consideration. A Member of the House of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, who is a Commissioner for the Revenue in <hi>Ireland,</hi> can testifie that the Customes there encreased this year to the value of Twenty five thousand Pounds, by the Import of 2500 Tun of <hi>French</hi> Wine, brought in pursuant to the Articles of <hi>Limerick;</hi> and if our Trade with <hi>France</hi> be not opened, we shall still have <hi>French</hi> Wines and other Commodities from thence brought in to us by the <hi>Danes, Swedes,</hi> and <hi>Dutch;</hi> the last whereof, as well as our Allies in <hi>Flanders,</hi> have lately taught us by Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perience, that a Commerce of Trade is not inconsistent with a State of War. We had much better have in our own Bottoms what have been and will be brought to us by Foreigners: For, not to instance in other <hi>French</hi> Merchandises, it is notoriously known that we have had <hi>Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paigne Wine</hi> (the undeniable Product of <hi>France)</hi> by the way of <hi>Flanders</hi> and <hi>Holland,</hi> at so great a rate it could not be sold in Taverns here for less than 10 <hi>s.</hi> a Flask.</p>
            <p>Foreigners thus carrying away our Trade, is a great <hi>Grievance;</hi> and if this, with our <hi>other Grievances</hi> be redress'd, and Care be taken that no more <hi>Money</hi> be given than what is absolutely necessary for the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>servation and Safety of the Nation, and that what be given be duly ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied for the uses intended, the People will part with their <hi>Money</hi> the more <hi>chearfully,</hi> and more <hi>moderate Taxes</hi> than what we are now affrigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted with the Apprehensions of will defray the necessary Expences of the War.</p>
            <p>If any of our Representatives shall not think fit for private ends of their own to doe these things, and shall prefer their own private Gain and Advancement before the publick Good; such must expect that the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:64195:4"/> People will never more chuse them to serve in <hi>Parliament:</hi> But we hope for better things, and are willing to believe they will approve them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves to be the true Conservators of the Liberties of <hi>England,</hi> and to take care to redress our <hi>Grievances,</hi> particularly in <hi>dismissing all foreign Forces,</hi> and justly and duly <hi>paying</hi> all our <hi>English</hi> by <hi>Sea</hi> and <hi>Land,</hi> which will so encourage our Soldiers, and unite us all at home, that no true hearted <hi>Englishman</hi> will be terrified or affrighted with the apprehension or rumour of any foreign Invasion whatsoever.</p>
            <p>Having in this Paper taken notice of the Barbarity used towards a free-born <hi>Englishman</hi> in <hi>Scotland,</hi> by Torture and Imprisonment contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to Law; that I may not seem partial, by concealing the Inhumanity lately used towards Prisoners in <hi>England,</hi> I shall give an Instance of such Barbarity, that I was very unwilling to credit the Relation, till I was throughly convinced of the Truth from the solemn Asseverations made by persons of undoubted Credit and Reputation.</p>
            <p>Two Foreigners and an <hi>Englishman</hi> were committed this last Summer Prisoners to <hi>Newgate</hi> as Spies, by a Warrant from a Minister of State, and by <hi>Order</hi> kept in <hi>Irons</hi> under so close a Confinement, that no per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son, except the Gaolers, was permitted for a long time to speak to them, see them, or send them any Relief; and if the <hi>Irons did not enter their Souls,</hi> it did so deeply their Flesh, that <hi>Major Richardson,</hi> now or lately Keeper of <hi>Newgate,</hi> and not much fam'd for <hi>Tenderheartedness,</hi> was moved in Compassion towards them, of his own accord, to strike off their <hi>Irons,</hi> give them <hi>Plaisters</hi> to heal their <hi>Sores,</hi> and move the Ld. Ch. Just. that they might be brought to Tryal; but his Lordship seeing their <hi>Mittimus,</hi> was pleased to say, <hi>Being committed as</hi> Spies, <hi>they were Prisoners of State, and he could take no cognizance of them;</hi> therefore their Names were not inserted into the Calendar of the Prisoners, which every Sessions is presented to the Judges, in order to the <hi>Gaol-Delivery. Major Richardson</hi> afterward made Application on their behalf to the <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nister of State</hi> by whose <hi>Order</hi> they were committed, who with a more than usual Clemency was pleased to reply, <hi>KNOCK THEM ON THE HEAD;</hi> and, as if to induce him to obey his Order, said, <hi>No Body knew where they were, nor could any discover but from him what became of them:</hi> And what is become of them is very worthy to be inquir'd into by the <hi>Parliament,</hi> who upon Enquiry will find, that one of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said Prisoners by his barbarous Usage is so distracted, that he is fitter to be an Inhabitant of <hi>Bedlam</hi> than <hi>Newgate;</hi> and if any Humanity hath been shewed to any of them, it hath onely been very lately, upon the approach of the Sitting of the Parliament.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>